Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Newsletter Collection, 1910-2005 RL.00733
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Main Newsletter Series, 1910-2018
  - 1975-1978, JWT News, 2 folders (Box MN19)
    Some issues combined. December issues dated Christmas 1976, 1977.
  - 1978-1980, JWTNews, 2 folders (Box MN19)
    Published bimonthly 1978-1979, quarterly in 1980.
  - 1982-1986, J. Walter Thompson News (including index 1982-1985), 4 folders (Box MN19)
    Published quarterly.
  - Breaking News, 2010-2017; 1184 document files; approx. 142MB (Digital-materials RL00733-SET-0001)
    Scope and Contents
    Missing 2015
  - Fast Forward, 2017-2018; 59 document files; approx. 3.8MB (Digital-materials RL00733-SET-0001)
- Domestic Newsletter Series, 1935-2005
  - Offices Subseries, 1935-2005
    Includes newsletters published by or focused on the activities of specific JWT offices. The frequency and regularity of publication of the newsletters vary substantially, from office to office and from year to year. See also the Other Newsletters Subseries for newsletters published by these offices related to specific issues in advertising. Organized alphabetically by office, therein by title. Runs may be incomplete within a particular year.
    Restrictions to access: Materials less than 15 years old are closed to non-JWT users. Where an item has been removed from containers and relocated, a dummy folder has been placed at the item's logical location within the container list, with the title enclosed by brackets and its physical location noted.
    - Atlanta
      - Monthly Happenings, 1982-1986, 3 folders (Box DO1)
        Office, client, and personnel news.
      - [ Owl and the Lamp, 1992-1993: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN1] (Box DO1)
    - Chicago
      - Consumer Response, 1980-1985 (Box DO2)
        Addresses issues in marketing, merchandising, and consumer behavior.
      - Information Center Flash, 1970-1973, 6 folders (Box DO2)
        Excerpts from magazines and newspapers addressing American business and society. Usually issued twice per week by the Information Center (less frequently and with shorter excerpts towards end of run). Continues JWT Library Flash.
      - JWT Library Flash, 1959, 1962, 1964, 1966-1968, 5 folders (Box DO2)
        Excerpts from magazines and newspapers addressing American business and society. Usually issued daily by the Information Center. Most holdings in 1962 and 1967. Continued by Information Center Flash.
      - [ Listener, 1993: Removed to Restricted Oversize Newsletters, Box ROV1] (Box DO2)
      - Michigan Avenews, 1970-1973, 3 folders (Box DO3)
        Office, client, market, and personnel news. Frequency of publication varies from biweekly to bimonthly.
      - Move Memos, 1989 (Box DO3)
        Newsletter concerning issues surrounding move of the office to the 900 North Michigan Avenue address.
      - Newsletter J. Walter Thompson Chicago, 1982-1983 (Box DO3)
        Light office and personnel news. Published every six months.
      - Sales Promo Update, 1983-1984 (Box DO3)
        Memoranda addressing promotional campaigns. Frequency of release varies from weekly to monthly. First two memos labeled Promotion Update.
      - [ Talker, 1992-1998: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN1] (Box DO3)
      - [ Talker Online, 1998-1999: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN1] (Box DO4)
      - Weekly News Digest, 1968-1969, 7 folders (Box DO4)
        Agency, office, and client news from the Chicago office; also reports on general American business news.
      - Westwords, 1978 (Box DO4)
        Light office and personnel news. Also covers Los Angeles and San Francisco offices. Published monthly.
    - Detroit
      - Detroit Ad-Vocate, 1974 (Box DO5)
        Office and personnel news. Published bimonthly.
      - Detroit Thompson Times, 1978-1980, 1982-1986, 4 folders (Box DO5)
        Light office and personnel news. Published twice a year, 1978-1980, and bimonthly, 1982-1986. Holdings spotty for 1984-1986. Includes JWT edition of 1983 March issue of Monthly Detroit.
      - FOB Detroit, 1966-1973, 3 folders (Box DO5)
        Light office and personnel news. Published bimonthy and monthly late 1972-1973.
      - [ Ford/Thompson Times, 1999-2005: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN1] (Box DO5)
      - [ JWTimes, 1995-1998: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN1] (Box DO5)
      - JWT Detroiter, 1975-1977 (Box DO5)
        Light office and personnel news from the Detroit office. Includes several photographic essay supplements.
      - JWT Directions: The Newsletter of J. Walter Thompson/Detroit, 1983 (Box DO5)
        Essays on issues in marketing and advertising, particularly relating to the automotive industry.
      - Mail Call, 1950-1951 (Box DO5)
        Direct mail, direct marketing issues and campaigns.
      - News from J. Walter Thompson Detroit, 1988-1994 (1991-1994 folder removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN1), 4 folders (Box DO5)
        Office, client, and personnel news. Published 4-5 times per year.
      - This Week in Detroit, 1956-1962, 10 folders (Box DO6)
        Light office and personnel news.
    - Los Angeles
      Also see Westwords, 1978, filed with the Chicago Office newsletters.
      - J. Walter Trumpet, 1989 (Box DO7)
        Office, agency, client and personnel news. Published roughly monthly.
      - JWT Times, 1985-1986 (Box DO7)
        Office, agency, client, and personnel news. Published roughly monthly.
      - Thompson Times, 1974-1976 (Box DO7)
    - New York
      - [ 402 Lex, 1982-1986: Removed to Oversize Newsletters, Box OV2] (Box DO8)
      - Finger-Tip Facts on Business, 1951 (Box DO8)
      - Flagship, 1975-1976 (Box DO8)
        Office, client, and personnel news. Published weekly. Continues JWT Friday.
      - Flash, 1937-1938 (Box DO8)
        Office, client, and personnel news. Also includes some news from other offices, both domestic and international. Published weekly. Continues News Flash.
      - Information Center, 1983 (Box DO8)
        Information regarding reference resources available from the office's Information Center.
      - Inside NYO, 1976-1978, 2 folders (Box DO8)
        Light office and personnel news. Published roughly biweekly.
      - J. Walter Thompson Company New York News, 1970-1973, 5 folders (Box DO8)
        Head title varies: New York New York New York; New York New York; New York; New York News. Office and personnel news. Usually published biweekly. Frequent minor changes in title and subtitle. Continues New York News (1963-1970). Continued by JWT Friday.
      - Junior News, 1935-1936, 4 folders (Box DO8)
        Byline reads: Issued by and for the Apprentice Group of the New York Office... Primarily covers broad issues in advertising; also some agency and office news. Published monthly. Continues J.W.T. Co. Junior News.
      - JWT Friday, 1973-1975, 5 folders (Box DO9)
        Office, client, and personnel news. Published weekly. Continues J. Walter Thompson Company New York News. Continued by The Flagship.
      - [ JWT Front and Center, circa 1942-1945: Removed to Oversize Newsletters, Box OV2] (Box DO9)
      - Keep in Touch: A Monthly Guide to What's Happening in Art, Fashion, Theater, Film and Music, 1975-1976 (Box DO9)
        Covers New York cultural scene. Compiled by the Creative Department. Subtitle varies.
      - New York News, 1963-1970, 1972, 7 folders (Box DO9)
        Office, client, and personnel news. Published weekly. Some issues were published as the single back page of the main newsletter, J. Walter Thompson Company News. If an issue cannot be found, check the Main Newsletter Series Boxes to see if the issue might have been inserted into the corresponding issue of the J. Walter Thompson Company News. Continued by J. Walter Thompson Company New York News.
      - The New York Thompson, 1978-1982 (Issues for 1978-1981 removed to Oversize Newsletters, Box OV2) (Box DO9)
        Light office and personnel news from the New York office.
      - News Flash, 1937 (Box DO9)
        Office, client, and personnel news. Also includes some news from other offices, both domestic and international. Published weekly. Continued by Flash.
      - People: Monthly Bulletin of the J. Walter Thompson Company, 1937, 2 folders (Box DO10)
        Articles on advertising and broader issues in society and business. Magazine format.
      - Previews, 1962, 1965, 1967 (Box DO10)
        Reviews and summaries of new holdings of the New York office's Information Center.
      - Project 466, 1981 (Box DO10)
        Newsletter informing New York staff of issues related to summer 1981 move from 420 Lexington Avenue to 466 Lexington Avenue.
      - Service Newsletter, 1942-1945, 3 folders (Box DO10)
        Reports news from JWT staff serving in the United States and Allied armed forces in World War II. Published monthly. Most but not all staff mentioned came from New York Office, the rest from both domestic and international offices.
      - [ Target, 1991-1992, 1994: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN1] (Box DO10)
    - San Francisco
      - [ Change, 1995-1996: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN1] (Box DO11)
      - Earthquaking News, 1973 (Box DO11)
      - J. Walter Thompson Company News, 1966-1968 (Box DO11)
        Light office and personnel news. Inserted into the main JWT newsletter.
      - Madcap Melodies, 1985-1986 (Box DO11)
        Light office and personnel news. Published every one to four months.
  - Divisions Subseries, 1974-2000
    Newsletters published by JWT divisions and subsidiaries. Organized alphabetically by division name, and then alphabetically by name of publication.
    - Brouillard Communications
      - Communications Watch, 1981-1987, 6 folders (Box DO12)
        Subtitled ...an overview of major trends and developments in the world of communications, particularly from the corporate point of view. Published monthly in New York.
      - Fog Talk, 1982-1987, 6 folders (Box DO12)
        Office, client, and personnel briefs. Published monthly in New York. Continues Inside News. Continued by Foghorn.
      - Foghorn, 1987-1990 (Box DO12)
        Office, client, and personnel briefs. Published monthly in New York. Continues Fog Talk.
      - Inside News, 1981-1982 (Box DO12)
        Office, client, and personnel briefs. Published monthly in New York. Continued by Fog Talk.
    - Dialog
      - Dialog Among Us, 1974 (Box DO12)
        Division, client, and personnel news. Published monthly.
    - JWT Group
      - Letter from the Chairman, 1983-1984 (Box DO12)
        Periodic briefings on broad company news.
    - JWT Specialized Communications
      - [ Live Wire, circa late 1990s-2000: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN1] (Box DO12)
    - Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein
      - LGFE Newsletter, 1984-1985 (Box DO12)
        Light office and personnel news from the corporate advertising division. Published monthly in New York.
    - Thompson Recruitment Advertising (Formerly named World Wide Agency.)
      - The Client Tell, 1980-1985, 5 folders (Box DO12)
        Employment and recruitment news and issues. Published bimonthly (later quarterly) from division's office in Baltimore.
      - Thompson Today, 1981-1985, 21 folders (Box DO13)
        Weekly newsletter of Thompson Recruitment Advertising. Division, office, and client news. Recruitment issues and news, with many case studies. Published from the Baltimore office.
      - Thompsonline, 1984-1985, 2 folders (Box DO13)
        The Employee Newsletter of Thompson Recruitment Advertising... Personnel news from the division's United States offices. Published quarterly from Los Angeles office.
  - Other Newsletters Subseries, 1940-1999
    Newsletters produced by various offices that focus on issues of broad company interest. Organized alphabetically by name of newsletter.
    - 60 Seconds: News and Reviews from Media Resources and Research, 1985-1989, 2 folders (Box DO14)
      Brief summaries of news from television, radio, computers, and other related areas. Published biweekly by the Chicago office.
    - Change in the Marketplace, 1976-1977 (Box DO14)
      A periodical bulletin from J. Walter Thompson Co. covering topical issues of concern to marketers. Covers a broad range of consumer products and issues. Published by the New York office.
    - Consumer Briefs, 1987 (Box DO14)
      General American consumer news. Published by the Strategic Services Department of the New York office.
    - Electronic Media Update, 1979-1986, 7 folders (Box DO14)
      News and issues in television, cable, and other sectors of the media industry. Published monthly by the New York office.
    - Food for Thought, A Marketing Report from JWT, 1957-1962, 2 folders (Box DO15)
      National supermarket news. Published by the Merchandising and Trade Relations Division of the Chicago office.
    - Food Service News, 1960-1961 (Box DO15)
      News from the food service industry. Published irregularly by the Chicago office.
    - [ In the News, 1995, 1998-1999: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2] (Box DO15)
    - Industry News Digest, 1969-1970, 6 folders (Box DO15)
      News summaries from retailing and industry. Published every few weeks by the Marketing Services Department of the New York office for account representatives.
    - J. Walter Log, 1987 (Box DO15)
      Newsletter of the JWT Archives.
    - [ J. Walter Thompson Kid Stuff, 1994-1995: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2] (Box DO15)
    - J. Walter Thompson World, 1989-1992 (1991-1992 folder removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2) (Box DO15)
    - J. Walter Thompson Worldwide Update, 1986-1987 (Box DO15)
      Highlights of agency, office, client, and senior staff news, events, and awards for offices, both domestic and international. Published by the New York office for JWT executives.
    - J. Walter World, 1988-1989 (Box DO15)
      Highlights of agency, office, client, and senior staff news, events, and awards for offices, both domestic and international.
    - JWT Campaign News, 1972-1973 (Box DO15)
      On soaps, detergents, toiletries. For the use of JWT groups on Unilever accounts. Covers both domestic and international campaigns. Published bimonthly.
    - JWT Company World, 1963, 1970-1972, 3 folders (Box DO16)
      Magazine-format overview of company activities, history, and personnel. 1963 issue is a mock-up copy. Starting with the Sept. 1970 issue the title becomes J. Walter Thompson Company World. Published roughly monthly.
    - JWT Greenwatch, 1990, 1993 (1991-1993 folder removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2) (Box DO16)
    - JWT World Highlights, 1973-1975, 1977, 2 folders (Box DO16)
      Agency, client, and staff news for both domestic and international offices. Circulated only to JWT executives. Published every few months. Includes division notes and text of two speeches by Don Johnston.
    - J.W.Trends, 1974-1977, 1990-1992, 1994 (1990-1994 folder removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2), 12 folders
      Brief notes about business, technological, and social trends... Published weekly by the Chicago office's Information Center.
      - 1974-1975, 1-5 of 12 folders (Box DO16)
      - 1976-1977, 1990-1992, 1994 (1990-1994 folders removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2), 6-12 of 12 folders (Box DO17)
    - Management News Summary, 1982-1986, 4 folders (Box DO17)
      Highlights of agency, office, client, and senior staff news, events, and awards for offices both domestic and international. Published every one to two months by the New York office for JWT executives.
    - Matter of Fact: News and Comment from the JWT Marketing Research Dept., 1966-1967 (Box DO17)
      Media and market research news. Published several times per year.
    - Media Report, 1966-1985, 31 folders
      Includes Network Notes.
      - 1966-1974, 1-12 of 31 folders (Box DO18)
      - 1974 (Box DO18a)
      - 1975-1982, 13-24 of 31 folders (Box DO19)
      - 1983-1985, 25-31 of 31 folders (Box DO20)
    - Merchandising News, 1940 (Box DO20)
      News of merchandising from across the United States and from various industries as well as the armed forces. Published from the New York office.
    - New Products Bulletin, 1978 (Box DO20)
      Single-page notices of new product introductions.
    - Once Over Lightly, 1979-1986 (Box DO20)
      One-page discussions of topics in marketing research and planning. Each issue written by single member of the Research and Planning Department in the New York office. Frequency of publication varies from bimonthly to annually.
    - Print Capsules, 1987 (Box DO20)
      News from the magazine and newspaper publishing industries. Published bimonthly by the Chicago office.
    - Profit-Sharing Plan News, 1950 (Box DO20)
      Information about JWT profit-sharing plans for staff.
    - Skilled Techniques in Guiding Group Action, 1956-1960 (Box DO20)
      Articles on group activities and dynamics. Not obviously related to advertising issues. Topics addressed include creative and visual arts, fund-raising, and food and nutrition. Published by JWT's Educational Service in the New York office.
    - White Papers, 1990-1993 (1992-1993 folder removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2) (Box DO20)
      Monographic reports on special topics.
    - [ World News Roundup, 1997-1999: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2] (Box DO20)
- International Newsletter Series, 1929-2004
  Includes newsletters published by JWT's international offices. Whether or not JWT maintained more than one office in a particular country, usually one newsletter covered the market news of the whole country or major regions as well as the specific news of the offices (for example, The Commodore's Log of Canada, reporting from the Montreal, Toronto, and Vancouver offices, and Boletim JWT of Brazil covering the São Paulo and Rio de Janeiro offices). The newsletters are usually in the dominant language used by the local office, although some are in English.
  In general, holdings are uneven. The two main periods where the holdings are deepest are the late 1950s to the middle of the 1960s and the first half of the 1980s, perhaps due to JWT events at the 1964-1965 New York World's Fair and the 1984 Epcot Swap Shop. The one nearly complete collection of international newsletters is the run of Round the Square, published by the London office from 1951 to 1986.
  Organized by geographical area in the following order: Canada; Latin America; Europe; and Asia/Pacific/Africa. Countries are then listed alphabetically, and then publications are listed alphabetically, except for general publications that cover all of Latin America and all of Europe. These items are found under the General heading at the beginning of each geographical area.
  - Canada
    - The Commodore's Log, 1974-1976, 3 folders (Box IN1)
      Agency and office news from the Toronto, Montreal, and Vancouver offices. In English.
    - J. Walter Thompson Company News, 1970 (Box IN1)
    - OK! (with corrections), 1959-1963 (Box IN1)
      Light news and personalities of the Toronto office. Issued monthly. In English.
  - Latin America
    - General
      - Aquí Latinoamerica, 1966-1967 (Box IN2)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from JWT's offices throughout Latin America. Published monthy, in Spanish.
      - Qué pasa in JWT AmericaLatina, 1982 (Box IN2)
        Agency and personnel news from JWT's offices in Latin America. Published in Caracas, in English.
    - Argentina
      - Bolétin J.W.T.A., 1956 (Box IN2)
        Office, client, and personnel news from Argentina. Published quarterly (?) by the Buenos Aires office, in Spanish.
      - Bolétin del Centro de Informaciones de JWTA, 1968 (Box IN2)
        Published bimonthly, in Spanish.
    - Brazil
      - A Régua T: boletim bimestral de J. Walter Thompson Company do Brasil, 1958 (Box IN2)
        Office, client, and personnel news from Brazil. Published bimonthly, in Portuguese. Covers São Paulo, Rio de Janeiro, and Porto Alegre offices.
      - Boletim JWT: órgão informativo mensual da J. Walter Thompson Brasil, 1964-1968 (Box IN2)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from Brazil. Published monthly, in Portuguese. Covers São Paulo and Rio de Janiero offices.
      - Notícias JWT, 1956 (Box IN2)
        Agency, market, and personnel news from Brazil. Published monthly, in Portuguese. Covers São Paulo and Rio de Janeiro offices.
      - Tudo Bem na JWT Brasil, 1982-1985 (Box IN2)
        Agency, market, and personnel news from Brazil. Published several times per year, in Portuguese. Covers São Paulo and Rio de Janeiro offices.
    - Chile
      - Lo que pasa en JWT Chilena, 1986 (Box IN2)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from Chile. Published by Santiago office, in Spanish.
    - Colombia
      - Qué pasa en Atlas, 1985 (Box IN2)
        Office and personnel news from Colombia. Published for Atlas (Bogotá) office, in Spanish.
    - Guatemala
      - Apcunoticias: Boletin informativo de APU de Guatemala, 1974-1975 (Box IN2)
        Office and personnel news for Agencias Publicitarias Centroamericanas Unidas, JWT's affiliate for Guatemala, El Salvador, Honduras, Nicaragua, Costa Rica, and Panama. Published bimonthly, in Spanish.
    - Mexico
      - [ Bitácora, 1992: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2] (Box IN2)
      - Qué Hay de Nuevo en JWT Mexico, 1983-1985 (Box IN2)
        Agency and personnel news from Mexico. Published three times per year by the Mexico City office, in Spanish.
      - Temas Thompson, 1978-1982 (Box IN2)
        Agency and personnel news from Mexico. Published quarterly (?) by the Mexico City office, in Spanish.
    - Peru
      - Qué Pasa en JWT Perú, 1983-1987 (Box IN2)
        Agency and personnel news from Peru. Published by the Lima office, in Spanish.
    - Puerto Rico
      - Llegando, 1978-1980, 1984 (Box IN2)
        Office and light news for Martí, Flores, Prieto, Comunicaciones, Inc., JWT's affiliate in Puerto Rico. Published in Caparra Heights, in Spanish.
    - Venezuela
      - Entre nosotros: bolétin informativo interno, 1970 (Box IN2)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from Venezuela. Published irregularly by the Caracas office, in Spanish.
      - Qué pasa en JWT Venezuela, 1985 (Box IN2)
        News from the Caracas office. In Spanish.
  - Europe
    - General
      - [ Commodore, 1993-1995: Removed to Restricted Newsletters, Box RN2] (Box IN2)
      - European Managers Monthly Digest, 1977-1978, 3 folders (Box IN3)
        Agency, office, personnel, and general political and economic news from all JWT European offices. Published for executives. In English.
      - [ Out of the Blue, 1998-2004: Removed to Restricted Oversize Newsletters, Box ROV2] (Box IN3)
    - Austria
      - Vienna Report, 1966 (Box IN3)
        Office, client, and personnel news. In German.
    - Belgium
      - Belgian Bulletin, 1960-1961 (Box IN3)
        Agency, client, and personnel news from Belgium. Published by the Antwerp office, primarily in English, with some French and Flemish.
    - France
      - Common Market Newsletter, 1959-1961 (Box IN3)
        General business and trade news, covering France, the Common Market, and other parts of Western Europe. Published several times per year by the Paris office, in English.
      - Informations JWT (later: Informations JWT Paris), 1961-1964 (Box IN3)
        Office and personnel news from France. Published several times per year by the Paris office, in French.
    - Germany
      - JWT Aktuell, 1983 (Box IN3)
        News of advertising campaigns. In German.
      - JWT Mittwoch Report, 1975, 1984 (Box IN3)
        Agency and office news from the Frankfurt office. In German. Includes one "Newcomer of the Month" cover in 1984.
      - JWT Report Frankfurt, 1961, 2 folders (Box IN3)